

Ms. Vaishnavi Srinath

🗣 Bangalore, India 🛛 🗠 vaishnavi.srinath.wk@gmail.com 🔪 9738872250

in vaishnavi-srinath-36511312a 🕠 myopicyeti.wordpress.com

A little bit about me

I have 4 years of professional experience. After two years as an engineer, I furthered my education with an MBA in sales and marketing. This academic background has equipped me to work in diverse industries, including IT, retail, and SaaS, where I have honed skills in product and digital marketing, customer sales, use case studies, marketing strategy, market research. My startup background has instilled in me a strong work ethic for both groundwork and strategic planning. I look forward to challenging opportunities that foster learning and shared successes.

Professional Experience

Marketing and Sales Manager, Distill.io □

05/2022 - present | BANGALORE, India

Distill is a website change monitoring tool that makes tracking website updates, automated and simplified.

- Planned and executed product marketing activities, encompassing feature launches, use case-specific campaigns, promotional initiatives, and informative webinars.
- Authored and published weekly blogs to enhance content marketing efforts.
- Designed and deployed solution landing pages to drive customer engagement and showcase product utility.
- Emphasized SEO optimization, managed LinkedIn Ad Campaigns, implemented Reddit Ads, executed backlink-building strategies, and enhanced website domain authority.
- Analyzed customer reviews on the Chrome extension store to drive increased downloads.
- A/B tested Ads, content strategies on various platforms
- 3X organic website traffic by strategically grouping keywords, implementing internal linking strategies, and creating user-focused content, such as blogs, use-case articles, and DIY guides.
- Crafted customer pitch decks and led sales conversations, gathering consumer insights, while also structuring sales processes to monitor and maintain sales funnel activities.
- Identified use cases and created how-to video guides and led product demonstrations in B2B Sales pitches

Marketing Intern, Distill.io □

07/2020 - present | BANGALORE, India

- Ensuring engagement on product platforms like Product hunt, Indie hackers, Hacker News during product launches etc
- · Competitive analysis and market research, campaign planning and management
- Ideation for content marketing and creating persona specific blog posts
- Analysing features and use case compatibility and opportunities for monetization

Sales and Marketing Intern, Titan Company Limited

05/2020 - 06/2020 | BANGALORE, India

- Segmentation based on communities in the Karnataka region
- Identifying problem areas via customer conversations, conducting reserach calls and focus group discussions
- Identify cultural factors/ influences in jewellery preference and buying behaviour
- Showcase customer narratives about different players in the market
- Short term and long-term plans to increase Kannadiga customer base

Product Marketing Intern, *Progress Software* □

03/2020 - 07/2020 | BANGALORE, India

Created short videos and posters for social media during product updates and launches

- Research calls for NPD, understanding FAQs on the public and community forums and initiating creation of feature assets along with product evangelists
- Handled marketing campaigns for the Demand Generation team

Quality Assurance Engineer, Tata Elxsi

2017 - 2019 | BANGALORE, India

- Created and maintained project dashboard, tracked project health indicators and interfaced with clients for deliveries
- Performed release certifications, project audits for better CSAT
- Aided productivity-driven development by monitoring and reviewing KPIs and sprint planning via JIRA
- Performed root cause analysis and created a knowledge compendium for the project teams.

Education

MBA- Marketing and Sales Management,

2020 - 2022 | Manipal

T A Pai Management Institute

Secured **7.8 CGPA** and was the **topper** of my cohort, and was in the **top 10** of the batch

Bachelor's of Engineering,

2013 - 2017 | Bangalore

Visveswaraya Technological University (VTU)

Secured 74% and specialized in Information Science Engineering

PUC, Karnataka State Board, Narayana PU College

2011 – 2013 | Bangalore

Secured 82% with specialization in Physics, Chemistry, Mathematics and Computers

10th Standard, SSLC, Karnataka Board,

2001 - 2011 | Bangalore

Poorna Prajna Education center

Secured 94%

Awards

Dean's Honor roll for Excellence in Academics,

05/2022

T A Pai Management Institute, Manipal

First Rank for PGDM Marketing batch 2020- 2022,

05/2022

T A Pai Mangement Institute, Manipal

Toast Master Level 1, *Toastmasters District 121*

2021

2 Best speaker certificates and 4 Best Table topic speaker certificates

TATA Elxsi Bravo Award, TATA Elxsi

2019

I was conferred the award for streamlining processes and tools in 6 Airtel Projects

Organizations

Literary and Media Committee, TAPMI,

03/2021 - 03/2022 | Manipal

Co-Convener of the committee

- Branding TAPMI, Literary event management, handling social media accounts, merchandising and branding.
- Planning and leading a team of 44 members

Toastmasters, *Member*

2020 – 2021 | Manipal

Completed level 1 certification with 2 best speaker and 4 best table topic speaker awards

Skills

Ahrefs, ScaleNut (Content creation), SurferSEO, Sales conversations, Content marketing, Market research, ChatGPT, UberSuggest (SEO marketing), Canva (Designing), Sprout Social (Social Media Management), Microsoft Office, Adobe Lightroom (Photo editing), Google analytics, LinkedIn Campaign Manager, Microsoft Designer

Interests

Gardening, Trekking, Cycling, Aerial Silks, Blogging,

Traveling (I've toured Italy, France, Spain, New York, Los Angeles, California, Minnesota, Agra, Rajasthan, Kerala, Nepal, Darjeeling, Sikkim, Himachal, Kanyakumari and more.),

Freelance content writer (*Creative merchandising, Ad copies, start-up presentation decks, brand stories, etc.*)

Projects

Usecase blogs, *Technical articles researched and written by me* https://distill.io/blog/ ☑

Product tutorials, How-to guides, and screencast videos, scripted and produced by me https://www.youtube.com/playlist \square